Guide to the Consumer Reports. Sylvia Lane papers, 1954-1978 and undated RL.11822
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Sylvia Lane papers
1954-1978 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11822
0.8 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Sylvia Lane was an economist who served on the Board of Directors of Consumers Union 1975-1977. The Sylvia Lane papers consist primarily of drafts, notes, reprints and published reports of Lane's advocacy and professional research writings. Subjects include consumer education, credit and credit discrimination, economic development, food distribution, health and medical care costs, housing and real estate, low-income communities and individuals, and sales and other taxes. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Professional Files; Research Project Reports
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Sylvia Lane was an economist who served on the Board of Directors of Consumers Union 1975-1977.
Sylvia Lane was born in 1916 in New York. She graduated from Berkeley (AB, 1934; MA 1936), Columbia (MA, 1937) and the University of Southern California (PhD, 1957) with degrees in economics and finance. Lane held a number of Professorships: Assistant Professor, University of Southern California (1947-1960); Associate Professor of Economics and Finance, San Diego State University (1961-1965); Associate Professor of Finance and Associate Director of the Center for Economic Education, California State University at Fullerton (1965-1969); Chairman, Department of Finance, California State University at Fullerton (1967-1969); Professor of Agricultural Economics, University of California, Davis (1969-1976). She died in 2013.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Sylvia Lane papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Board of Directors records
Consumer Reports. Lynn Jordan papers
Collection Overview
The Sylvia Lane papers consist primarily of drafts, notes, reprints and published reports of Lane's advocacy and professional research writings. Subjects include consumer education, credit and credit discrimination, economic development, food distribution, health and medical care costs, housing and real estate, low-income communities and individuals, and sales and other taxes.
Consumer education; Economics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Economics -- History; Women economists -- United States -- History; Economic development; Credit; Medical care -- United States -- History; Taxes -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Lane, Sylvia
- Professional Files, 1954-1978 and undated; 1
  - Articles and dissertation abstract, 1954-1978 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Chapter XIII Petitioners; Comment on Proposed Changes in the Charitable Deduction; Distributional Equity of the Food Stamp Program; Economics of Consumer Class Actions; Ecomonics of the Low-Income Mortgagor Counseling Program; Effectiveness of Public Income Redistributive Programs on Lower Income Groups; Familiarizing Students with Unfamiliar Merchandise Sources; Food Distribution and Food Stamp Program Effects on Food Consumption and Nutritional Achievement of Low Income Persons in Kern County California; Graduated Sales Tax; Housing the Underhoused; Petitioners Under Chapter XIII of the Bankruptcy Act; Rising Cost of Medical Care; Socio Economic Study of Marginal Credit Risks; Sub-Marginal Credit Risks; Submarginal Credit Risk Classification
  - Essays, 1960-approximately 1969 (Box 1)
    Includes: Buying Intelligently; Evaluation of Proposals for Revision of the California State Sales Tax System; Further Regressive Effects of Exise and Sales Taxes; Personal Bankrupts, Debtors and Debt Counselees
  - Manuscripts--Consumer Agencies and the Theory of Consumer Demand, undated (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts--Consumer Credit, undated (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts--Consumer Savings and Savings Institutions, undated (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts--Mortgage Credit, undated (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1959-1969 (Box 1)
    Includes: Consumer Agencies and the Theory of Consumer Demand; Housing the Underhoused; Marginal Credit Risk Study; Some Economic Aspects of the Provision of Adequate Medical Care in the United States; Strengthening the Family Economic Functioning Through Effective Counseling
- Research Project Reports, 1965-1972; 2
  - Advisory Commission on Tax Reform Researcher's Tentative Report, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Conduct of Escrows by California Real Estate Brokers, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Content Outline for a One Semester, Secondary Level American Economy Course, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Housing the Underhoused: The California Studies, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Preliminary Evaluation of the Section 237 Housing Counseling Program, 1972; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Resource Document for a High School Course in The United States Economy, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Syllabus for a One Semester, Secondary Level American Economy Course, 1965; 2 folders (Box 2)